Alen Pelin

alen.pelin@gmail.com · 0436306699

linkedin.com/in/alenpelin alenpelin.com (blog) github.com/alenpelin

My primary focus is contracting in Sitecore-oriented technology world, but it can also extend to great permanent position as Senior/Architect/Lead Sitecore developer.

I have excellent development & analytical skills, as well as an ability to communicate with client to truly understand real business requirements.

My professional credo consists of four pieces:

- know and use tools, that best for the task, and use them efficiently;
- spot and automate time-consuming actions to focus on important matters;
- never stop learning new technologies including other tech stacks
- it is essential to invest your personal time to support IT community by helping others and building open source tools

8+ years working in Sitecore Corp. gave me unbeatable knowledge of the technology stack, access to and learning from multiple businesses around the globe built with SC products.

Apart from common "best practices" I had chance to work with lots of different not-so-much-successful implementations (and helped to save them) and extract certain anti-patterns that often are more useful than simply knowing best-practices.

Earlier this year I started exploring world of digital agencies, using my expertise and developing real things for real clients in less formal environment.

Experience

Loud & Clear (as a contractor) Sr. Sitecore Developer, May 2018 – currently

- Developing greenfield project based on Sitecore Commerce 9 with SXA with Helix
- Building internal Sitecore framework for new projects to start with

Sitecore Corporation, Product Support Services Lead Software Engineer, April 2010 – May 2018

•••

Alen Pelin

Sitecore Corporation, Product Support Services Lead Software Engineer, April 2010 – May 2018

- Technical consulting Sitecore customers and partners
- R&D projects, building hotfixes and improvements to products
- Designing, developing and coordinating Sitecore tools and extensions
- Resolving complex cases and escalated support tickets
- Establishing support team procedures, guidelines and standards
- Sitecore CMS code quality audit and bug fixing
- Other (training, mentoring, code review, writing documentation, automating tasks etc.)

Signature Projects:

- Sitecore Diagnostics Service (due to be released in Sitecore 9.0.3)
- Sitecore CMS parts: Configuration Roles engine, Administration component
- Sitecore Instance Manager
- SBOS Accelerators

Technical Skills

- ASP.NET MVC / Core, Angular / React, SQL Server / MongoDB, Azure PaaS
- Agile, KISS, DRY, Patterns, Microservices, TDD

Education

- Dnipro National University
 2006 2011, Masters in Math
- IT Step Academy
 2007 2009, Software Development

Extras

NodeJS, TypeScript, Angular Material, Gulp, PowerShell, CSS, Azure Service Bus, Azure Blob Storage, AppVeyor, VSTS, GitLab, Jekyll;

HyperV, Windows Server, DNS, AD, SQL Server, TeamCity, Networking,